Ben Hensor

Front End Developer

benhensor@gmail.com • +44 07811 469 975 • Bristol, UK • benhensordev.com(tbc) • Github • LinkedIn

Profile

As a former sound designer for film, tv and commercials, I bring a unique perspective to the world of tech and Front End Development. After almost a decade in the film industry, I made the decision to enroll in the School of Code Bootcamp to pursue a new challenge.

With a Masters from the National Film & Television School, I have a strong foundation in collaborative working, creative problem-solving and attention to detail. These skills have proved invaluable in my transition to web development, where I am constantly challenged to find elegant solutions to complex problems.

My commitment to continuous learning and growth is key to my approach. I am excited to bring my skills and passion for development to a new role, where I can contribute to a team and continue to expand my skills.

Skills

JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Jest, Playwright, Git/Github, Figma, Trello, Express, Node JS

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer

School of Code

• Final Team Project:

- 5 week development sprint to create (insert project here)
- Full stack application using: React, JS, Jest, Playwright, Express, PostgreSQL, and Node JS.
- · Adopted Agile methodologies into our team through stand ups, retros, sprints and project management.
- Utilised a variety of project management and design tools to realise the solution from initial concept through to build.
- Delivered product presentation to industry representatives.
- 16 week coding bootcamp focused on team building and group learning.
- · Developed coding and communication skills through pair programming, workshops, group discussions and hackathons.
- Introduced to new concepts and technologies almost daily and applied them to solidify learning and build upon new and existing skillsets.
- Undertook self-guided study to enhance learning through documentation and tutorials.
- · Applied design thinking to project briefs and used ideation methods to explore the requirements from a user perspective.
- Learnt to read and search error codes to solve issues.
- · Mid-point project week creating fully functioning MVP from ideation to build and presenting to industry repsresentatives.
- Learned to develop software testing frameworks and problem solving.

03.2023 - 07.2023 Birmingham, **United Kingdom**

Sound Editor & Dubbing Mixer

Self-Employed

05.2013 - 12.2022

• An award-winning sound editor, working on a wide range of independent feature films, short films, animations, documentaries and commercial projects.

Bristol, United Kingdom

- Fully proficient in Pro Tools, Logic Pro, Ableton, Euphonics, Eucon and RX technologies.
- Field Recording creating sound libraries in a variety of formats and locations around the world.
- Worked closely with creative professionals as part of a crew collaborating to deliver immersive experiences.
- Developed strong relationships with various production companies and individuals around the world.
- Maintained regular learning to keep abreast of developments in technologies and techniques.

Education

MA Sound Design for Film & Televison

National Film & Television School ☑

2011 – 2013 Beaconsfield, United Kingdom

HND Audio Production

University of the West of England

2009 – 2011 Bristol, United Kingdom